In October 16th, 2016, I went on holiday,
technically
backpacking to Australia.
I just wanted to see what the personal
training scene was
like in Australia.
So I jumped on a plane one way,
got to Sydney, and
needless to say, it was bloody good.
Feel like I'm doing an interview.
Got the job already, James.
No need to be nervous.
Now,
over that three-month training period,
I said, "Do you know what?
Why don't you train with me online?" to a
few of my old clients and a few people on
my email list, and in that moment,
I think I invented online personal
training.
But here's the thing. After a few months,
I got a taste, and I decided there and
then, I'm not going back to work,
and I didn't, and I haven't,
and it's been,
17, 18, 19, 20.
It's been eight years working online
without a boss,
just using these two things here.
And I make a good living,
and I'm going to give you a very simple
strategic guide
that you can implement to do the same.
People have problems.
And most people for a job solve problems,
even something like a barber.
Think about it. Problem, hair's too long.
Solution, I'll shorten it for you.
Mechanic. Problem,
lights on the dashboard. Solve it for you.
Me.
Problem,
my arm isn't long enough to hold a camera
really far away.
Declan solves it.
Almost every single business
is in the realm of problem-solving.
Some people, not all people,
have the beautiful opportunity to solve
those problems
online. If you solve people's problems,
chances are they will relate to you.
Think of it this way. You might think
that you and I are friends or
that we have a
relationship, or you might have even said,
"Oh, that James Smith, he's a bit of a
legend." Thank you. But the truth is,
if I didn't solve your problems,
we wouldn't
have this. Every video I put out
is in some regards to help you solve a
problem.
And this is the crazy thing I want you to
think about.
Out of whoever follows you,
whether 1,000 or 10,000 people,
I want you to help
95% of people for free. Yes.
So they'll come up to you one day in the
bakery, fist bump you, go,
"I love your stuff.
Thanks for solving my problems." Cool.
You do that well enough,
and eventually you can solve someone's
problem offline.
For instance,
you're going to create some kind of asset
with someone's problem in
mind. Now you're probably wondering,
why James did you decide to do it about
landing pages? Well,
a friend of mine called Ed Lawrence solves
people's problems
about growing YouTube channels,
but then he realized the people whose
problems he
solved had another problem. And
that problem was
that they didn't know which videos
were attributing
which bits of sales to the business.
So he solved their problems by creating
something called RevTrack.
And some of you might have already started
using it.
And I realized that in my own YouTube
channel, the highest clicks we're getting
from videos was about landing pages.
So I had to create some kind of asset.
Now, right now at the moment, people
are still thinking 10 years ago,
"I might make
a calorie calculator." Rinsed.
"I might make a recipe book."
Rinsed. "I might offer people some advice.
I'll give them 15 tips." Tips?
No one woke up today going,
"I wish I had some
tips." Some people go, "Oh,
I'll give you a blueprint." No one went,
"Oh, fucking
hell. Do you know what I need?
A blueprint." They've not done it.
Whatever it is you're using to collect
emails, because I managed to travel the
world with a calorie calculator before it
was rinsed, you've got to make it sexy.
I went out and printed
that on a bit of paper. A3.
Got a nice little laminate.
Wave it in people's faces.
I spent an hour designing it.
Abraham Lincoln, what did he say, Declan?
"Give me six hours to chop down a tree,
and I will spend three hours
sharpening the axe."
When you're solving problems on social
media, the next thing
you need to think about
is what can you do to get
that person's information?
What problem can you solve further?
Whether it's fat loss, weight loss,
accountancy. Hell, lower back pain.
This is the most integral part.
And you can gauge the interest of it.
I waved that bit of paper around the other
day, 584 comments.
That's 508 email addresses.
Can you do better than that, James? I can.
5,000 comments. Well, actually,
a lot of them are DMs because they wanted
it
private.
This carousel post the other day got me
12,000 email
addresses.
If you want to know your capacity to work
online, travel the world, be a
digital nomad,
whatever the young people are calling it,
everyone seems to think
it's this, but it's not. It's this.
Because the more email addresses you have
in your database, the more
people you can reach out to about
potentially doing business with you.
Everyone online is talking about social
media. They're talking about hooks.
They're talking about this.
They're talking about that.
My main YouTube channel I haven't touched
in months.
My main Instagram I barely use.
The reason that my businesses can stay
afloat, like
Nutonic and my coaching app,
is because of the emails.
I'm not sure how many times I can say this
to people, but please
create an amazing automation for your
emails.
So that means that if someone joins today,
tonight, tomorrow, whatever, they get
taken on a journey of understanding your
values, your proposition, your offering,
everything it is, so
that you can have a lovely landing page.
Then guess what?
Once you set this up,
it takes a few hours.
My job in the mentorship
is to help you with your social media to
stop making shit
content, to stop having rubbish reels,
and to stop little things like your jump
cuts aren't right,
there's too much dead space above you,
whatever it is, right?
Once we tick that off,
I then help people with their squeeze
pages. I go onto it.
I go, "Rinsed." I go, "That's dry." I go,
"That's boring." I go, "No one wants
tips." Once we've done that,
we then look into their email automations.
Oh,
I gave them three bits of advice over
three weeks.
They go, "Oh, 21 emails." They go, "No,
one email once a week." That's dog shit.
Do better. Cool.
So we fix their email automation.
Then we look at their landing page.
Landing page, different fonts,
too small text, too scattered, built with
MailChimp. This looks shit.
Whatever it is,
then we fix the landing page. Okay?
Once those four things are done,
they're done. We park them to the side.
Once you've created those things, this
is where your business lives and
dies. Behind every good online business,
their funnel's set up.
All you then need to do
is feed the pony at the front end.
This YouTube channel, over 30,000 subs.
The Instagram, now at 30,000.
We'll go through the Instagram
funnel just really quickly. Clips,
chatbot, video.
The clips on Instagram,
sometimes I share it with my main page.
People watch the clips,
they want to see the full video,
chatbot sends them the
full video. Cool.
Those of you on YouTube just go straight
to the full video.
Every single long-form video we put out,
including this one, people then click on
the links in the description.
They click on the links in the
description.
They go through to the landing pages.
They go through to the landing pages,
and then they buy.
Once you have these things set up,
all we need to do and all you need to
do is keep creating content.
And content then becomes like
little logs that you go get every day
and you put them on the fire.
Like little bits of kindling
that you put on to keep the business
alive.
Then one log just so happens to be more
flammable than others and the whole fire
goes [whooshes] .
And then what usually happens
is the fire then gets dim because
you stop putting logs on it because the
fire was too big.
Behind every single digital nomad
and person that works online,
they have the
funnel and the strategy set up so
that their job on a daily basis is just
to add content to the equation. That's it.
That is it.
Even now, this video, I put it on YouTube,
clients pop out.
We put clips on Instagram,
My job is just to send traffic to
websites, and the way that we do that
is just to
add content to the top of the equation.
Once you build out all of these important
things and do it properly, it's pretty
much what I teach you.
I'm not even a business expert.
I just teach people about that process
and that funnel.
All you will need to do for the next few
years is just to put out one piece of
content a day. "Oh, but James,
I didn't have time to make a video." Do a
carousel
post.
"I didn't have time to do a carousel
post." Well, you're full of shit.
Screenshot a tweet. How hard is this?
What's a... There we go.
Why don't we just put something
controversial like this?
Hire slow, fire fast.
Should we put rest in peace Lucas?
Yeah, that blonde guy
that Simon Squibb sent. No longer.
We going to get into it?
Probably not. So even me, right?
For any of you out there that say, "Oh,
I don't
have time to post today," you can
literally just screenshot flipping Thread.
Honestly, if you want to work online,
create a flow from ass to mouth, or
technically mouth to ass.
From socials to landing page.
And then your job on a daily basis
is to just put content on top
and wait for the
clients to pop up. That's it.
You don't even need to understand
business.
You just need to understand that.
The links are in the description as usual.
Grab them, get onto it.